ARVINDH C. VIGNESH

Senior Associate Data Analytics



Chennai, India

cvarvindh@gmail.com

+91-9444422199

https://github.com/Arvindh99 https://portfolio-cv-jd2w.onrender.com/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/arvindh22199

SKILLS

Python Programming

Pandas, Numpy, Matplot, Seaborn, Plotly, Regex

Microsoft Office

Excel, Powerpoint, Word, Outlook, OneNote

Machine Learning Algorithm

K nearest neighbor, Linear Regression, Support Vector Machine, Random Forest, Logistic Regression

Visualization tools

Tableau, Power BI

Statistics

R Programming

SQL

AutoCAD

Aspiring Data Analyst with 2.5 years' work experience along with a strong acumen to learn the business skills and adapt to work in diverse environments

- Energetic personality with a keen attention to learning and problem-solving abilities in all domains of my work.
- Recognized for consistently demonstrating resourcefulness by working well in teams and completing the tasks within deadlines.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sutherland Global Services

(June, 2021 – Present)

Senior Associate Data Analytics

- Revenue cycle management analysis for the hospitals
- Data segregation to identify the different sub divisions of hospital departments, patients, insurance payers, payments received/pending
- Data collection from generic formats to structured excels to maintain database
- EXCEL and Python programming are used for analysis
- Weekly Zoom calls/meetings and presentation of the analytics done every week to the management

Sutherland Global Services

(Jan, 2021 – May 2021)

Data Analyst Intern

Data Exploration and Revenue analysis for USA hospitals using Python coding

EDUCATION

Anna University, India

(May 2022 – Present)

MBA, Business Analytics (Online)

SRM Institute of Science and Technology, India

(Aug 2019 – May 2021)

M.Sc. Health Data Science (8.55/10)

Chettinad Hospital and Research Institute, India

(July 2016 – May 2019)

B.Sc. Medical Genetics (8.11/10)

PROJECTS

Analyze the risk factors affecting mental well-being of students during pandemic

M.Sc. Project (Apr 2020 – Aug 2020)

Determination of miRNA as Biomarker for diagnosis of Cardiovascular diseases

B.Sc. Project (Dec 2018 – May 2019)

CERTIFICATIONS

Foundation in Data Science – OneFourth Labs

(Mar 2022)

Business Analytics and Text Mining Modelling using Python - NPTEL

(Sep 2021)

Python for Data Science - NPTEL

(Sep 2019)

INTERESTS

Video & Music Editing Painting